A Guide to the S. S. Van Dine Photograph Collection, 1900-1939
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
S. S. Van Dine Photograph Collection, 1900-1939
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9701-b
This collection contains 97 photographs.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library by John Loughery, New York, New York, on October 1, 1992.
Scope and Content Information
Photographs assembled by John Loughery while researching his biography of Willard Huntington Wright, entitled Alias S. S. Van Dine. The collection includes scenes from S. S. Van Dine - Philo Vance movies; photographs of Van Dine, his wife, and dogs; photographs of his brother's artwork; and photographs of drawings and caricatures of him by Thomas Hart Benton, James Montgomery Flagg and Langdon Smith together with some miscellaneous items.
Contents List
- A Photograph from the Benson Murder Case Motion Picture ca. 1930, B & w photograph
- Photographs from the Bishop Murder Case Motion Picture 1930, 4 b & w photographs
- Photographs from the Canary Murder Case Motion Picture 1927-1928, 10 b & w photographs
- Photographs from the Dragon Murder Case Motion Picture 1934, 2 b & w photographs
- Photographs from the Greene Murder Case Motion Picture ca. 1929, 3 b & w photographs
- A Photograph from the Kennel Murder Case Motion Picture 1933, B & w photograph
- Photographs: Miscellaneous 1901-1935, 12 b & w photographs
  Including the Arcadia Hotel in Santa Monica (the Wright's first home in California); the first page of two newspaper articles about Wright, "A Literary Vivisectionist" and "Los Angeles-City of Dreadful Night; California reactions to Willard's The Smart Set broadside; covers from The Smart Set for January and February, 1914; Scribner's ad for the first book of the Philo Vance series, 1926; and Van Dine at work in the penthouse (circa 1935).
- Photographs of the Artwork of Stanton Macdonald Wright 1913-1922, B & w, color photos; 7 items
  The brother of Willard Wright, including three copies of a portrait of Wright by Stanton Macdonald Wright.
- Photographs: Willard Huntington Wright 1900-1939, 23 b & w photographs
  Including two of Wright as a boy at the New York Military Academy, Bard Hall; one of Wright as the literary editor of the Los Angeles Times; photograph introducing Wright to the readers of The Smart Set; and a variety of photographs from later in his career when he had begun writing the Philo Vance mysteries.
- Photographs: Willard Huntington Wright Drawings & Caricatures 1916-1934, 7 b & w photographs
  Including a drawing of Wright by Thomas Hart Benton, caricature of Willard that appeared in the San Francisco Bulletin; a drawing by James Montgomery Flagg, used as a publicity photograph by Scribner for The Casino Murder Case; a caricature by James Montgomery Flagg of "The Real S.S. Van Dine" viewing him as a devil; and an engraved picture of Wright by Langdon Smith which appeared in The West Coast Magazine.
- Photographs: Willard Huntington Wright and his wife, Claire De Lisle 1930-1938, 9 b & w photographs
- Photographs: Willard Huntington Wright 1932-1938, n.d., 18 b & w photographs
  With his dogs and at the race track